# Wesley Chen

301-693-2251 | Reston, VA 20190 | weschen1996@gmail.com https://github.com/IdleScV | https://medium.com/@weschen1996

#### SUMMARY

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with a background in project organization. Possesses strong skills in team-building and project management that helps small teams deliver consistent and high quality results. Strong desire to create well organized systems & code structures as a result of previous experience in the high-end kitchen industry.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, JSON, Python, Ruby, SQL Development Tools: Express, Git, jQuery, Rails, React, Redux

Operating Systems: Linux (Ubuntu), OS X(Yosemite to Catalina), Windows (XP, 7, 8, 10)

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Path - Github(Front Back) | Demo Website

View and create the timelines of real or fictional people in detail or with a broader scope.

- Built with React, Rails, Firebase and Material-UI
- Limited fetch request & re-loading through persistent data which allows for a smoother user experience
- Created a separate work log file that allows for a more detailed & clear commit message system
- Implemented a responsive Javascript/CSS method which simulates zooming in on a timeline

## **Draw-Off** - Github( Front Back ) | Demo Website

A fun and collaborative party game where up to 8 players are given interesting prompts to draw and rate.

- Built with React, Rails, and Firebase and Material-UI
- Utilized Firebase for user authentication & password management
- Created rooms and live server interactions through custom backend routing

## Code Wars - Github( Front Back )

A coding challenge game where players compete 1 on 1 to see who solves the algorithm first.

- Built with vanilla JavaScript & Rails
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Simulates a live server through constant fetch calls
- Simulates a JavaScript IDE aka online coding environment using the browser's own developer console to output user's code accuracy.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Officina Resto Bar in Wholefoods Tysons, Tysons, WA - Assistant Kitchen Manager

11/2019 - 03/2020

- Created kitchen specific training guide which allowed for easier hiring of inexperienced workers
- Managed multiple restaurant schedules to increase efficiency for Wholefoods cafeteria
- Setup kitchen stations as part of opening team

## Luvi, New Orleans, LA - Junior Sous Chef

08/2018 - 06/2019

- Created recipe book for pre-existing and new dishes which increased consistency of final product
- Interacted with customers while working the sushi bar to enhance customer's experience

### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School: Immersive Software Engineer Boot Camp - Washington, DC

01/2020 - 05/2020

**Montgomery College,** Rockville, MD - Associates in Business Management

08/2019

International Culinary Center, New York, NY - Professional Culinary Arts

03/2017